[
    {
        "id": "01",
        "question" : "Question: What is the central bank of Nepal?",
        "options": [
            "Nepal Bank Limited",
            "Rastriya Banijya Bank",
            "Nepal Rastra Bank",
            " Agriculture Development Bank"
        ],
        "answer": "Nepal Rastra Bank"
    },
    {
        "id": "02",
        "question" : " Which organization regulates the securities market in Nepal?",
        "options": [
            " Nepal Rastra Bank",
            "Nepal Stock Exchange",
            " Securities Board of Nepal",
            " Ministry of Finance"
        ],
        "answer": " Securities Board of Nepal"
    },
    {
        "id": "03",
        "question" : " What is the main stock exchange in Nepal?",
        "options": [
            " Himalayan Stock Exchange",
            "Nepal Stock Exchange",
            "Everest Stock Market",
            " Kathmandu Stock Exchange"
        ],
        "answer": "Nepal Stock Exchange"
    },
    {
        "id": "04",
        "question" : "What is the currency of Nepal?",
        "options": [
            "Indian Rupee",
            "Bhutanese Ngultrum",
            "Nepalese Rupee",
            " Chinese Yuan"
        ],
        "answer": "Nepalese Rupee"
    },
    {
        "id": "05",
        "question" : "Which tax is the largest source of revenue for the Nepalese government?",
        "options": [
            "Income Tax",
            " Value Added Tax",
            "Excise Duty",
            " Customs Duty"
        ],
        "answer": " Value Added Tax"
    },
    {
        "id": "06",
        "question" : "What is the current monetary policy stance of Nepal Rastra Bank as of 2023?",
        "options": [
            "accommodative",
            "Easing",
            "Neutral",
            "Contractionary"
        ],
        "answer": "accommodative"
    },
    {
        "id": "07",
        "question" : "What is the corporate tax rate for general industries in Nepal?",
        "options": [
            "15%",
            "20%",
            "25%",
            "30%"
        ],
        "answer": "25%"
    },
    {
        "id": "08",
        "question" : " Which financial institution is primarily responsible for providing microfinance services in Nepal?",
        "options": [
            "Commercial Banks",
            " Development Banks",
            "Microfinance Development Banks",
            " Insurance Companies"
        ],
        "answer": "Microfinance Development Banks"
    },
    {
        "id": "09",
        "question" : " What is the primary law governing banking operations in Nepal?",
        "options": [
            "Company Act",
            " Banking Regulation Act",
            "Banks and Financial Institutions Act (BAFIA)",
            "Financial Institutions Act"
        ],
        "answer": "Banks and Financial Institutions Act (BAFIA)"
    },
    {
        "id": "10",
        "question" : "What is the standard VAT rate in Nepal as of 2023?",
        "options": [
            "10%",
            "12%",
            "13%",
            "15%"
        ],
        "answer": "13%"
    }
]